Guide to the John Kent Folmar's Collection on the Monongahela River Buffs Association, 1870-2015 AIS.2019.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
John Kent Folmar Collection on the Monongahela River Buffs Association
1870-2015
ULS Archives & Special Collections
AIS.2019.01
9 Linear Feet 17 boxes (and some items in a drawer and a flag)
This collection contains materials, collected by John Kent Folmar, related to the Monongahela River Buffs Association as well as the subject of Monongahela riverboats broadly. The Monongahela River Buffs Association aspired to preserve the history of the vessels and sailors who traveled along the Monongahela River. Dr. John Kent Folmar is an emeritus professor from the University of California, California, Pennsylvania, as well as a former member and president of the Monongahela River Buffs Association from 1980-1981, as well as 1990-2015 in addition to editing The Voice of the Mon newsletter.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acqusition Information
Gift of Dr. John Kent Folmar I on January 3, 2019.
Biographical / Historical
Dating back to late 18th century, the Monongahela Valley was a center of river boat production in what was then the American Northwest. After massive public works to make the Monongahela more navigable and facilitate westward-expansion, between 1811 and 1888, over 3,000 steam boats would be produced from various boatyards throughout the region. By the turn of the 20th century, river traffic was frequent and modestly safe, if not as popular a transportation method as the concurrently growing railroad network. The largest contribution of this industry in the 20th century was plying the waterways with barges loaded with coal to fuel the growing steel industry in Pittsburgh and beyond. In order to preserve this history, the Monongahela River Buffs Association was officially formed in Greensboro, Pennsylvania on May 9, 1978. The group went on to create a museum in 1986 in Monongahela, PA, focused on the Monongahela River as well as the sailors and vessels who worked on the river. In addition to the museum, the group hoped to more broadly preserve the history of the Monongahela River (as abbreviated as The Mon) and generate public interest in venturing out onto the river and protecting the river from pollution. Founding members included Ernest Gabler, a former deckhand/pilot of a river ferry, and Herman D. Bennett, who would go on to become the first editor of the group's newsletter, The Voice of the Mon. In 1986, the group moved to the second floor of the former Odd Fellows building in Monongahela, Pennsylvania. The group would stay there until they were forced to close in 2015 when a lack of attendance at the museum and there weren't enough members to keep the association going.
Dr. John Kent Folmar, an emeritus professor at California University of Pennsylvania, would take over as editor in 1981. Dr. Folmar would also become president of the group in 1990, serving both positions until 2015.
Arrangement
Series I. Navigation Charts and Maps, c. 1929-1985
Series II. Newspaper Articles and Clippings, 1944-2007
Series III. Pamphlets and booklets (Printed materials), 1934-2006
Series IV. Photographs, 1870-2005
Series IX. Postcards
Series V. Realia
Series VI. Record Books from Vessel, 1948-1972
Series VII. Scrapbooks, 1936-2005
Series VIII. The Voice of the Mon Newsletters, 1979-2015
Series X. Topical, 1897-1981
Series XI. United States Steel and Organized Labor Unions, 1923-1992
Series XII. Video Interviews, 1984-1994
Scope and Content Note
This collection is made up of navigational charts, printed materials, photographs, scrapbooks, postcards, The Voice of the Mon newsletters newsletters and DVDs of video interviews collected by John Kent Folmar, predominantly in association with the Monongahela River Buffs Association.
- Navigation Charts and Maps, c. 1929-1985; I.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains navigation charts, primarily for the Ohio, Allegheny, and Monongahela rivers. The charts are a mix of bound and blueprint formats, as well as a poster map of Pittsburgh Harbor.
  - Chart No. 186 – Ohio River: Pitt to Mouth (1911-14), c. 1929 (Drawer 12-19, Folder 1)
  - Chart no. 232 – Ohio River: Pitt to Mouth (1911-14) Wabash Island Bar Location of Dredge Cut, August 26, 1929 (Drawer 12-19, Folder 2)
  - Chart No. 234 – Ohio River: Pitt to Mouth (1911-14) Raleigh Bar Dredge Cut, c. 1929 (Drawer 12-19, Folder 3)
  - Chart No. 243 – Ohio River: Pitt to Mouth (1911-14), c. 1929 (Drawer 12-19, Folder 4)
  - Chart No. 244 – Ohio River: Pitt to Mouth (1911-14), c. 1929 (Drawer 12-19, Folder 5)
  - Chart No. 244 – Ohio River: Pitt to Mouth (1911-14) Walkers Bar Location of Dredge Cut, August 26, 1929 (Drawer 12-19, Folder 6)
  - Chart No. 249 – Ohio River: Pitt to Mouth (1911-14) Pryors Island Dredge Cut, c. 1929 (Drawer 12-19, Folder 7)
  - Chart no. 250 – Ohio River: Pitt to Mouth (1911-14) Sisters Island Bar Location of Dredge Cut, August 25, 1929 (Drawer 12-19, Folder 8)
  - Navigational Chart, Allegheny River, January, 1985 (Drawer 12-19, Folder 9)
  - Navigational Chart, Mississippi River, February, 1938 (Drawer 12-19, Folder 10)
  - Navigational Chart, Monongahela River, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Navigational Chart, Ohio River, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Navigational Chart, Ohio River – Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania to Powhatan Point, Ohio, January, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Navigational Chart, Ohio River – Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania to Powhatan Point, Ohio, January, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Navigational Chart, Ohio River – Powhatan Point, Ohio to Foster, Kentucky, January, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Navigational Chart, Ohio River – Powhatan Point, Ohio to Foster, Kentucky, January, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Pittsburgh Harbor Map, April, 1952 (Drawer 12-19, Folder 11)
- Newspaper Articles and Clippings, 1944-2007; II.
  Newspaper clippings, primarily from Pittsburgh-based newspapers, related to the Monongahela River, riverboats, events related to the river such as the Lewis and Clark Expedition and the 1949 Steamboat Race, river infrastructure such as locks, dams, and bridges, and articles relating to the history the river, boats, and towns along the river.
  - 1949 Steamboat Race Between Homestead and William Larimer Jones, Pittsburgh (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Always a River: The Ohio River and the American Experience (Exhibit) Pittsburgh Post-Gazette Articles, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Boat Related, 1944-1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bridges, 1951-1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Homestead Steamboat, 1950-1961 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Lewis and Clark Bicentennial, 2003-2006 (Oversize 11, Folder 1)
  - Lewis and Clark Expedition Bicentennial, 2000-2003 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Locks and Dams, 1957-1971 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Pittsburgh Sun-Telegraph "Our Flood in Pictures", March 16, 1956 (Oversize 11, Folder 2)
  - River Related Economics, 1946-1969 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - River Related History, 1940-2004 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - River Workers Committee Labor Union, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Sprague "Big Mama" Steamboat, 1959-2007 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - The Pittsburgh Press Sunday Roto, December 31, 1944 (Oversize 11, Folder 3)
  - The Pittsburgh Press Sunday Roto, September 22, 1968 (Oversize 11, Folder 4)
  - The Pittsburgh Press Supplement "Interconnecting Waterway", November 14, 1965 (Oversize 11, Folder 5)
- Pamphlets and booklets (Printed materials), 1934-2006; III.
  This series contains printed material related to the Monongahela, Allegheny, and Ohio rivers, as well as the ships and captains which may be found on them. This includes promotional materials for shipbuilders such as Dravo Corporation and Hillman Barge and Construction Company, issues of various magazines and other publications, rules for ship pilots, and a program from the launching of the B.F. Fairless towboat.
  - American Steamboat Album by Captain Frederick Way Jr., 1970 (Drawer 12-19, Folder 12)
  - Carnegie Steel Company – Voyage Number 100 program, January, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Dravo Corporation, Program for the Launching of the B.F. Fairless towboat, November, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Dravo Corporation Promotional Materials, c. 1940s (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Fast Lines: Getting Places During the Years 1800-1880, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Federal Register Volume 37 Number 156, August 11, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Hillman Barge and Construction Company Promotional Materials, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - James Rees & Sons Company shipbuilding illustrated catalog, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Jones & Laughlin Steel Corporation Promotional Materials, June, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Lewis and Clark Expedition Reenactment, c. 2003-2006 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - List of Coal Mines, Landings and Towns of the Monongahela & Allegheny, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Locks and Dams, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Old Main Magazine fourth issue, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Pennsylvania Heritage, Summer 2001 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Pennsylvania Heritage, Winter 2002 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Regulations Governing the Admission of Candidates into the United States Naval Academy as Midshipmen and Sample Examination Papers, June, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Southwestern Pennsylvania Number 4, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Specimen Examination Questions for Licenses as Master, Mate, and Pilot of Central Western Rivers Vessels, April, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Sperry Gyroscope Company Promotional Materials, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - St. Louis Shipbuilding – Federal Barge, Inc. Promotional Materials, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Steel Facts, August, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - The American Waterways Operators, Inc. Promotional Materials, 1956-1965 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - The Artist Looks at Industrial Pittsburgh (Exhibit) program, June, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - The Sohioan, July, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - The Steamer Sprague by Jack Custer, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - U.S. Army Corps. of Engineers publications related to the Monongahela, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Union Barge Line 150th Tow program, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Various rulebooks for Pilots, Masters, and Mates, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - W.P. Snyder Jr. steamboat related, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Photographs, 1870-2005; IV.
  Photographs, primarily of riverboats, but also of river scenes (such as a festival or the aftermath of a flood). If photographs were originally in the same photo album, there are kept together as a subseries/folder. All of the loose photos have been arranged into additional subseries based on the type of vessel.
  - Digital Prints, undated; 1.
    Digital images printed out on paper. Many of the images are scans of historical photographs.
    - Digital Prints, Black & White, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Digital Prints, Color, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Oil Wells, Brownsville, Pennsylvania covered bridge, and Lewis and Clark celebration bound digital prints, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Elizabeth, Pennsylvania 100th Anniversary and Riverboats, undated; 2.
    The photographs were in photo album pages within an unlabeled white binder. A note inside the binder identified 10 as "Elizabeth's 100th Anniversary" and the rest had more generic categories (steam towboats, tour/towboats, & POMEROY, O. FLOOD – 1937).
    - A.B. Sheets and U.S. Steel Excursion Barge, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Beacon, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Delta Queen, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Elizabeth, Pennsylvania 100th Anniversary River Parade, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Mongah, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Pomeroy, Ohio Flood, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Tom Dodsworth, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Volcano, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Monongahela River Steamboats Album, 1870-1957; 3.
    The photographs were originally in a 3-ring binder. They have been arranged alphabetically into folders by the vessel name.
    - Index (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - A.B. Sheets, Hillman Coal & Coke Co., T0005, 1921-1947 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Acorn, Consolidated Coal Co. (Combine), T0032, April 17, 1897 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Alicia, Brown Coal & Coke Col. T0101 and 0102, 1913-1926 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Aliquippa, Jones & Laughlin Co., T0103, 1914-1952 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Andrew Axton, Diamond Coal Co., T0128, 1903-1906 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - B.F. Fairless, Carnegie Illinois Steel Corp., T0186, 1935-1952 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - B.F. Jones Co., Jones and Laughlin Co., T0187, 1907-1952 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Beacon, Pittsburgh Coal Co., T0209, 1917-1937 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Braddock, American Steel and Wire Co., T0291, 1916-1926 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Champion Coal, Combine, T0373, 1935-1954 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Charles R. Cox, US Steel Corp., T0385, 1948-1960 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Charles T. Campbell, Campbell Trans. Co. +2 co. later, T0390, 1936-1955 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Charlie Clarke, W.H. Brown & Sons + 3 co. later, T0398, November 1911 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Collier, W.H. Brown/U.S. Steel Corp., T0464, 1914-1939 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Crescent, Pittsburgh Coal Co./J.K. Davison Bros., T0520, 1937-1952 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Cruiser, Brown's Line/Combine, T0530, 1923-1935 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Crusader, Combine, T0532, 1908 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Dewing and Sons, Dewing Lumber Co., T0596, 1894-1915 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Donora, American Steel/Carnegie Steel Co., T0622, 1924-1950 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Duquesne, U.S. Steel Corp., T0645, 1929-1964 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Edgar Thomson, Carnegie Steel Co., T0685, 1919-1953 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Fallie, McKinley Coal Co./Combine, T0794, 1894-1921 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - George Roberts, Horner & Roberts, T0929, 1870-1891 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Henry L. Laughlin, J&L Steel Co., T1088, 1905 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Harry L. Roemer, Monessen Coal and Coke Co./Hillman Trans. Co., T1090, 1936-1944 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Iron City, Iron City Sand Co., T1199, 1912-1948 (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - J.E. Leonard, J.E. Leonard, Brownsville PA, T1243, 1903-1905 (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - J.H. Hillman, Hillman Trans. Co., T1253, 1927-1951 (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - J.H. McGrady, McGrady-Rodgers Co., T1255, 1927-1944 (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - J.L. Perry, Carnegie-Illinois Steel Co., T1264, 1945-1957 (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - James A. Rankin, J&L Steel Co., T1319, 1948-1952 (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - James A. Lose, Carnegie-Illinois Steel Co., T1323, 1938-1948 (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - Joe Carter, Hillman twice/C. Zubik, T1383, March 6, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 34)
    - John A. Ailes, Combine, T1442, 1892-1902 (Box 17, Folder 35)
    - John W. Hubbart, Campbell Tans. Co. +2 co. later, T1444, 1920-1932 (Box 17, Folder 36)
    - Leona, Capt. R.J. Hiernaux, Charleroi, PA, T1571, 1929-1941 (Box 17, Folder 37)
    - Juniata, American Stele and Wire co., T1480, 1900-1925 (Box 17, Folder 38)
    - Little Fred, O'Neil Coal Co./Combine, T1605, 1881-1915 (Box 17, Folder 39)
    - Maggie, Samuel Clarke & Sons/James Jones/Combine, T1691, 1881-1902 (Box 17, Folder 40)
    - Marion, McClain Sand Co., Point Marion, PA T1723, November 21, 1923 (Box 17, Folder 41)
    - Mongah, Pittsburgh Coal Co., T1855, 1937-1957 (Box 17, Folder 42)
    - Monitor, Diamond Coal and Coke Co./Carnegie Steel Co., T1860, 1907-1925 (Box 17, Folder 43)
    - Monongahela, Carnegie Steel Co./Ohio Barge Line, T1862, 1927-1955 (Box 17, Folder 44)
    - William G. Glyde and Pacific No. 2, Carnegie Steel Co. and Pacific Coal Co./Combine, T2662 and T1998, 1922 (Box 17, Folder 45)
    - Ranger, Combine T2111, 1903-1935 (Box 17, Folder 46)
    - Robert Jenkins, T.M. Jenkins & Co./National Trans. Co., T2179, 1881-1924 (Box 17, Folder 47)
    - Sailor, J&L Steel Co., T2226, 1924-1951 (Box 17, Folder 48)
    - Sam Barnum, Hillman Coal & Coke Co., T2238, 1912-1917 (Box 17, Folder 49)
    - Swan, U.S. Corps of Engineers, T2367, June 9, 1915 (Box 17, Folder 50)
    - T.P. Roberts, U.S. corps of Engineers, T2382, 1906-1926 (Box 17, Folder 51)
    - Thomas Moses, Carnegie-Illinois Steel Co., T2419, 1936-1957 (Box 17, Folder 52)
    - Titan, J&L Steel Co., T2443, 1930-1953 (Box 17, Folder 53)
    - Vesta, J&L Steel Co., T2521, 1931-1948 (Box 17, Folder 54)
    - Vulcan, J&L Steel Co., T2550, 1910-1951 (Box 17, Folder 55)
    - W.C. Jutte, Peoples Coal Co. +3 co. later, T2555, 1901-1917 (Box 17, Folder 56)
    - Warren Elsey, J&L Steel Co., T2613, 1919-1953 (Box 17, Folder 57)
    - W.C. Sutherland, Hillman Trans. Co., T2653, 1936-1939 (Box 17, Folder 58)
    - Wm. Larimer Jones, J&L Steel Co., T2671, 1930-1953 (Box 17, Folder 59)
    - W.P. Snyder Jr., Carnegie Steel/Crucible Fuel Co., T2587, 1945-1953 (Box 17, Folder 60)
    - Wilmot, T2691, 1900-1907 (Box 17, Folder 61)
    - Youghiogheny, Carnegie Steel Co., T2707, 1927-1935 (Box 17, Folder 62)
  - "Odds & Ends: Monongahela and Elsewhere" album, undated; 4.
    The photos were inside of a photo album labeled "Odds & Ends: Monongahela and Elsewhere" on the front cover. There is a mix of color photos from circa 1974 as well as some black and white photos from the 1930s and earlier. The majority of the color photos depict towboats and barges whereas the black and white photos mainly depict various locks, steamboats, and dredge crews.
    - Brownsville, Pennsylvania, Lock #5, c. 1930s (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Clipper, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Diesel Towboats and Barges, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Dredge Crews, c. 1930s (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Elizabeth Smith, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Emsworth Lock, Ohio River, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Harriet Sue, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - I.C. Woodward, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - J.C. McClain, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Joe Sokol, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Kanawha River and Lock, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Martin G., undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Rhododendron Showboat, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Swan, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Unidentified Buildings, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Unidentified Coast Guard Vessel, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Unidentified Man, undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Unidentified River Scenes, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Souvenir booklet of images from Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, c. 1900-1910; 5.
    Scopes and Contents
    This is a bound set of 82 images (printed on the front and back of each page) from the Pittsburgh area, dating from the early 1900s. The back cover has a red label which reads "W.A. MC-CORMICK." Inside the back cover, there is also a cursive, handwritten note that reads "Souvenir of Pittsburg [sic] From [illegible] F Beek [or possibly Beck]."
    - Souvenir booklet of images from Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, c. 1900-1910 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Vessels and River Scenes, undated; 6.
    Photographs of various vessels and various scenes, primarily on the Monongahela, Allegheny, Ohio, and Mississippi Rivers. Photographs are sorted by the name of the vessel or scene. If a diesel towboat and steamboat both had the same name, they were split into two folders.
    - A.B. Sheets, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - A.C. Ingersoll Jr., undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - A.I. Baker, undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - A.O. Ackard, undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - A.R. Budd, undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Acorn, undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Active, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Aetna Louisville, undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Aliquippa (Diesel Towboat), undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Aliquippa (Steamboat), undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Allegheny, undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Allied Ashland, undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - B.F. Fairless (Diesel Toboat), undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - B.F. Fairless (Steamboat), undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - B.F. Jones Jr., undated (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Barges, undated (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Beacon, undated (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Belle McGowan, undated (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Betty, undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Boaz, undated (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Boonesboro, undated (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Braddock, undated (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Brownsville, Pennsylvania, Monongahela River Flood, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Busy Bee, undated (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - C.D. Scully Fireboat, undated (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - C.F. Hood, undated (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - C.I.S. 6, undated (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - C.W. Talbot, undated (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Cap'n Howder, undated (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Captain Alphin, undated (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Captain Anthony Comer memorial photo album, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Carnegie-Illinois Steel Corporation steamboat captains raising a World War II Treasury Department War Bonds "T" Flag, c. 1941-1945 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Champion Coal, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Charles R. Cox, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Charles R. Hook, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Charles T. Campbell, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Charley Jutte (sunk), undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Chickamauga, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Chickie, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - City of Huntington, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - City of Pittsburgh, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - City of Wheeling, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Clairton, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Clairton Mill Works Scenes, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Clipper, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Conqueror, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Crescent, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Cruiser, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - D.W. Wisherd, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Defender, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Delta Queen, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Destrehan, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Dixie, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Donna Lee, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Donora, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Duquesne, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - E.A. Woodruff, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - E.D. Kenna, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - E.K. Davison, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - E.L. Crain, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Edgar Thomson, undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Elizabeth, Pennsylvania Flour Mill, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Elizabeth, Pennsylvania River Festival, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Elizabeth, Pennsylvania River Festival Negatives, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Enterprise, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Forsythia, undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Fred Wilson, undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - G.W. McBride, undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - G.W. Thomas, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Gaiola, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Gambler, undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Gateway, undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Gateway Clipper's Liberty Belle, undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Gona, undated (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - H.B. Jordan, undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - H.D. Williams, undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - H.S. Douglas, undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Harvey Jordan, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Hatfield's Ferry II, undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Hawk, undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Hazelwood, undated (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Hecla, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Henry A. Laughlin, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Henry L. Hillman, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Henry Lourey, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Herbert E. Jones, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Hillman, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Hillman Barge & Construction Company Barges, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Holandez, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Homestead, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Humphrey, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - I. Lamont Hughes, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Inland, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Iron Age, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Iron City, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Ironsides, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - J.C. Richardson, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)